=Chasing Love=
= الحب =
=Episode 15=
= الحلقة 15 =
How is he?
كيف حاله
Princess,
الأميرة
the Seventh Prince
الأمير السابع
is in good health,
في صحة جيدة
you may rest easy.
قد ترتاحي بسهولة
Then why is he sweating so much?
إذًا لماذا يتصبب عرقًا؟
Does it mean
هل هذا يعني
he's feeble?
هل هو ضعيف؟
Ridiculous.
إنه سخيف
He's not feeble.
إنه ليس ضعيفا
Princess, if you're still worried,
الأميرة، إن كنت لا تزال قلقة
allow me to prescribe some medicine.
اسمحوا لي أن أصف بعض الدواء
I'll make sure after taking it,
سأتأكد من ذلك بعد أخذه
he'll be as vigorous
سيكون قويا
as a young man.
مثل شاب
What do you mean by that?
ماذا تعني بذلك؟
Are you saying I'm old?
هل تقول إنني كبيرة في السن؟
Well...
إذن
Off you go now.
لنذهب الآن
Yes.
نعم
Leave the prescription to me.
اتركي الوصفة الطبية لي
What,
ماذا
is your feebleness
هل ضعفك
upsetting you?
يزعجك؟
I'm perfectly strong.
أنا قوية جدًا
You want to give it a try?
هل تريدين المحاولة؟
Really?
حقًا؟
Can I really have a try?
هل يمكنني المحاولة حقًا؟
Yeah.
نعم
Release my acupuncture points.
أفرج عن نقاط الوخز بالإبر
Forget about it,
انسي الأمر
let's try again next time.
لنحاول مجددًا في المرة القادمة
You've got your hands full now.
أنت شبعت يديك الآن
My hands are empty.
يداي فارغتان
No, you're not.
لا، لست كذلك
What's this?
ما هذا؟
To be a competent husband to a princess,
ليكون زوجا كفؤا لأميرة
you must know how to cook and sew.
يجب أن تعرف كيف تطبخ والخياطة
Today,
اليوم
you'll spend half the day cooking and half sewing.
ستقضين نصف اليوم في الطهي والخياطة
Tomorrow, you'll spend half the day
غدًا، ستقضين نصف اليوم في ركوب الخيل ونصف اليوم في الموسيقى والشطرنج والخياطة
on horseback riding and half the day on music, chess, calligraphy and painting.
على ركوب الخيل ونصف اليوم على الموسيقى والشطرنج والخط والرسم
By rotating through these lessons,
عن طريق التناوب من خلال هذه الدروس
I'm sure you'll make progress soon.
أنا متأكد من أنك ستحرز التقدم قريبًا
I'm not doing this.
لا أفعل هذا
Do as I say. You must learn.
افعل ما أقول، يجب أن تتعلم
As your wish.
كأمنية لك
Do not blame me for being unteachable.
لا تلومني على أنني غير قابلة للتشابك
The threads are all tangled up.
الخيوط متشابكة
I can't do it.
لا يمكنني فعل ذلك
It's okay.
لا بأس
I'll show you how to untangle the threads.
سأريك كيف فكّ الخيوط
Thank you, mammy.
شكرًا لك يا أمي
Now you can continue embroidering.
الآن يمكنك مواصلة التطريز
Continue.
استمروا
Is he really sick?
هل هو مريضة حقًا؟
I have seen him,
لقد رأيته
he's not sick.
إنه ليس مريضا
Considering that her three previous husbands
بالنظر إلى أن زوجها السابق الثلاثة
had all died unnatural deaths,
قد ماتوا جميعا وفيات غير طبيعية
the princess was distraught
الأميرة كانت فاقدة
and overly concerned.
ويساورنا القلق الشديد
In your opinion,
في رأيك
how does the princess feel about the Seven Princes?
كيف تشعر الأميرة تجاه الأمراء السبعة؟
Well,
إذن
I've never seen her
لم أرها أبدا
so devoted to any man.
مكرسة جدا لأي رجل
In time,
مع الوقت
the one who will be the princess's husband will be the seventh prince.
الشخص الذي سيكون زوج الأميرة سيكون الأمير السابع
That's the man I chose.
هذا هو الرجل الذي اخترته
It's only been a few days
لم تمض سوى أيام قليلة
and he's charmed the princess to death.
وهدّم الأميرة حتى الموت
The gods are with me.
الآلهة معي
My great cause will surely come true.
من المؤكد أن قضيتي الكبيرة ستتحقق
That's the man I chose.
هذا هو الرجل الذي اخترته
He's so pretty.
إنه جميل جدًا
That's the parents I chose.
هذا هو الآباء الذين اخترتهم
You're so pretty.
أنت جميلة جدًا
Who are you?
من أنت؟
It's a secret.
إنه سر
Where did you come from?
من أين أتيت؟
I've come from where I came from.
من أين أتيت
You know smart talking, little kid.
تعرفين الكلام الذكي أيها الطفل الصغير
What is smart talking?
ما هو الكلام الذكي؟
When you meet someone
عندما تقابلت شخصا ما
called Donghua,
اسمه دونغهوا
he'll tell you.
سوف يخبرك
He's going to prick his finger.
سيثقب إصبعه
Oh no.
لا
You got to be careful
يجب أن تكون حذرًا
or I'll get worried.
أو سأشعر بالقلق
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Are you bashful now?
هل أنت خجولة الآن؟
I'm not.
ليس لدي ما
Cang Xiaoqi,
تسانغ شياوتشي
you're so cute now.
أنت ظريف جدا الآن
Why are you being so innocent,
لماذا أصبحت بريئًا جدًا؟
acting like a little kid.
تتصرف كالأطفال الصغار
Right, that little girl,
صحيح، تلك الفتاة الصغيرة
where is she?
أين هي؟
She was just flirting with me.
كانت تغازلني فحسب
Princess, do you always
يا أميرة، هل أنت دائمًا
like to flirt with strange men?
تريد المغازلة؟
You're no strange man.
أنت لست رجلًا غريبًا
You're my husband
أنت زوجي
and you're going to be the husband of the future Empress of Donglan.
وستكونين زوج إمبراطورة دونغلان المستقبلية
Are you jealous of yourself?
هل تشعرين بالغيرة من نفسك؟
You've got me wrong.
لقد أخطأت في كلامي
I have no interest in being your husband.
لا يهمني أن أكون زوجك
So what are you interested in?
فماذا تهتم به؟
I want to succeed in an imperial-examination, become an official and save the world.
أريد أن أنجح في فحص إمبراطوري، أصبح مسؤولا وأنقذ العالم
♪Soft and light, adore the bustle and hustle in life♪
♪ الصدع والضوء، يعصف بالحيوية والصخب ♪
♪You're a gust of wind blowing my river of love♪
♪ أنت فورة من الرياح تهمر نهري من الحب ♪
♪Your eyes are the galaxy I can't escape♪
♪ عيناك هما المجرة لا أستطيع الهروب ♪
♪I secretly conjecture what you think♪
♪ أنا أخفي سرا ما تعتقده ♪
♪It's soft and unpredictable♪
♪ إنه ناعم ولا يمكن التنبؤ به ♪
♪I clench my hand to feel your outline♪
♪ أنا أضطر للشعور بمخططك ♪
♪I vainly attempt to have you but fail♪
♪ أحاول عبثا أن أجعلك تفشل ♪
♪The wind blew toward me. He walked past and I missed♪
♪ لقد نفخت الرياح تجاهي لقد مشى الماضي اشتقت ♪
♪I'm waiting for a gust of wind and for you to approach me♪
♪ أنتظر شهية من الريح وأنت تقرب مني ♪
♪You're wind brushing past me accidentally♪
♪ أنت تتفاخر بي بعد قليل ♪
♪You flip my heart and make my thoughts of you a river♪
♪ أنت تقلّب قلبي وتجعل أفكاري عنك نهرًا ♪
♪Then you just fly away♪
♪ إذن أنت تسافر بعيدا ♪
♪I'm waiting for a gust of wind to blow toward me♪
♪ أنا أنتظر هباء من الرياح لتفسح لي ♪
♪I fantasize about him choosing me firmly like you♪
♪ أنا أتذمر من اختياره بقوة مثلك ♪
♪I know the love won't end well♪
♪ أعلم أن الحب لن ينتهي جيدا ♪
♪As love grows deep, silence deepens♪
♪ مع نمو الحب عميق، الصمت يتعمق ♪
♪It's soft and unpredictable♪
♪ إنه ناعم ولا يمكن التنبؤ به ♪
♪I clench my hand to feel your outline♪
♪ أنا أضطر للشعور بمخططك ♪
♪I vainly attempt to have you but fail♪
♪ أحاول عبثا أن أجعلك تفشل ♪
♪The wind blew toward me. He walked past and I missed♪
♪ لقد نفخت الرياح تجاهي لقد مشى الماضي اشتقت ♪
♪I'm waiting for a gust of wind and for you to approach me♪
♪ أنتظر شهية من الريح وأنت تقرب مني ♪
♪You're wind brushing past me accidentally♪
♪ أنت تتفاخر بي بعد قليل ♪
♪You flip my heart and make my thoughts of you a river♪
♪ أنت تقلّب قلبي وتجعل أفكاري عنك نهرًا ♪
♪Then you just fly away♪
♪ إذن أنت تسافر بعيدا ♪
♪I'm waiting for a gust of wind to blow toward me♪
♪ أنا أنتظر هباء من الرياح لتفسح لي ♪
♪I fantasize about him choosing me firmly like you♪
♪ أنا أتذمر من اختياره بقوة مثلك ♪
♪I know the love won't end well♪
♪ أعلم أن الحب لن ينتهي جيدا ♪
♪As love grows deep, silence deepens♪
♪ مع ازدياد الحب عميقا، الصمت يتعمق ♪
♪I'm waiting for a gust of wind and for you to approach me♪
♪ أنتظر شهية من الرياح ولك أن تقترب مني ♪
♪You're wind brushing past me accidentally♪
♪ أنت تتفاخر بي بعد قليل ♪
♪You flip my heart and make my thoughts of you a river♪
♪ أنت تقلّب قلبي وتجعل أفكاري عنك نهرًا ♪
♪Then you just fly away♪
♪ إذن أنت تسافر بعيدا ♪
♪I'm waiting for a gust of wind to blow toward me♪
♪ أنا أنتظر هباء من الرياح لتفسح لي ♪
♪I fantasize about him choosing me firmly like you♪
♪ أنا أتذمر من اختياره بقوة مثلك ♪
♪I know the love won't end well♪
♪ أعلم أن الحب لن ينتهي جيدا ♪
♪As love grows deep, silence deepens♪
♪ مع ازدياد الحب عميقا، الصمت يعمق ♪